<story-context id=".bmad/bmm/workflows/4-implementation/story-context/template" v="1.0">
  <metadata>
    <epicId>11</epicId>
    <storyId>genre-management-1</storyId>
    <title>Add Genre Edit Mode with Remove Functionality</title>
    <status>drafted</status>
    <generatedAt>2026-01-16</generatedAt>
    <generator>BMAD Story Context Workflow</generator>
    <sourceStoryPath>docs/sprint_artifacts/story-genre-management-1.md</sourceStoryPath>
  </metadata>

  <story>
    <asA>user managing my music genres</asA>
    <iWant>to enter an edit mode where I can remove genres from the main grid</iWant>
    <soThat>I can customize my genre selection and remove genres I don't use</soThat>
    <tasks>
      1. Add edit mode state management in genre-selection.tsx
      2. Add "Rediger" toggle button in section header (top-right)
      3. Add X remove buttons with conditional rendering (only show in edit mode)
      4. Implement genre removal with archive logic (soft delete)
      5. Add CSS styles for edit button and remove button in globals.css
      6. Disable genre selection when in edit mode
      7. Test on all screen sizes (mobile, tablet, desktop)
      8. Verify no console errors or warnings
      9. Commit changes and mark story ready for review
    </tasks>
  </story>

  <acceptanceCriteria>
    AC-1: "Rediger" button appears in genre section header (top-right)
    AC-2: Clicking "Rediger" toggles edit mode ON
    AC-3: In edit mode - Button text changes to "Ferdig", background becomes orange (active state), Red X button appears on each genre chip, Genre chips cannot be selected, Cursor shows "not-allowed" on hover
    AC-4: Clicking X button removes genre from grid
    AC-5: Removed genre is archived (not permanently deleted)
    AC-6: Clicking "Ferdig" exits edit mode
    AC-7: Edit mode state persists until manually toggled off
    AC-8: X buttons have smooth hover states (scale up, darker red)
    AC-9: No console errors or warnings
    AC-10: Works on mobile, tablet, and desktop
  </acceptanceCriteria>

  <artifacts>
    <docs>
      <doc>
        <path>docs/tech-spec-ui-modernization.md</path>
        <title>Tech-Spec: UI Modernization & Visual Refresh</title>
        <section>Project Context</section>
        <snippet>Comprehensive tech-spec for previous UI modernization epic (CR-001, CR-002, CR-007, CR-008, CR-009). Documents the orange/purple color scheme, simplified 2x2 genre grid, Lucide icons, and overall design system. Current story builds upon this foundation.</snippet>
      </doc>
      <doc>
        <path>docs/tech-spec-ui-modernization.md</path>
        <title>Tech-Spec: UI Modernization & Visual Refresh</title>
        <section>Existing Patterns to Follow</section>
        <snippet>Component Structure: Functional components with TypeScript, Props interfaces, "use client" directive, kebab-case files. Styling: Tailwind utility classes, cn() for conditional classes, CSS variables for theme colors. State: React hooks for local state.</snippet>
      </doc>
      <doc>
        <path>docs/epic-ui-modernization.md</path>
        <title>Epic: UI Modernization & Visual Refresh</title>
        <section>Implementation Complete</section>
        <snippet>All 5 stories completed (Color scheme, emoji removal, 2x2 genre grid, lyrics tabs, phonetic disable). Genre grid now shows 4 default genres with "+ Legg til sjanger" button. Status: COMPLETE.</snippet>
      </doc>
      <doc>
        <path>.bmad/docs/AIMusikk_Change_Requests.md</path>
        <title>Change Requests Document</title>
        <section>CR-003: Add Genre Edit Mode</section>
        <snippet>User request for ability to remove genres from main grid. Requires "Rediger" toggle button, red X buttons on chips in edit mode, soft delete/archive functionality. Part of Epic 11 (Genre Management & AI Assistant).</snippet>
      </doc>
    </docs>
    <code>
      <artifact>
        <path>src/components/genre-selection.tsx</path>
        <kind>component</kind>
        <symbol>GenreSelection</symbol>
        <lines>1-212</lines>
        <reason>Current implementation of genre grid. Already modernized with 2x2 layout and "+ Legg til sjanger" button. Need to add edit mode state, "Rediger" button, and X remove buttons to this component.</reason>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>src/components/genre-selection.tsx</path>
        <kind>state-management</kind>
        <symbol>useState hooks</symbol>
        <lines>50-54</lines>
        <reason>Existing state: genres, selectedId, isLoading, error, showAllGenres. Need to add editMode state and removeGenre handler function.</reason>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>src/components/genre-selection.tsx</path>
        <kind>component</kind>
        <symbol>Genre grid rendering</symbol>
        <lines>160-196</lines>
        <reason>2x2 genre grid with gradient buttons. Need to add conditional X button rendering inside each genre button, disable selection when editMode is true.</reason>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>src/lib/constants.ts</path>
        <kind>configuration</kind>
        <symbol>FEATURES</symbol>
        <lines>67-72</lines>
        <reason>Feature flags object. Can optionally add ENABLE_GENRE_EDIT_MODE flag (though story says to implement directly, not behind flag).</reason>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>src/app/globals.css</path>
        <kind>stylesheet</kind>
        <symbol>CSS variables</symbol>
        <lines>1-100</lines>
        <reason>Theme CSS variables for colors. Primary orange (#FF6B35), destructive red for X button. Use hsl(var(--primary)) for edit button active state, hsl(var(--destructive)) for remove button.</reason>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>src/components/ui/button.tsx</path>
        <kind>component</kind>
        <symbol>Button</symbol>
        <lines>all</lines>
        <reason>shadcn/ui Button component used throughout. Use for "Rediger" button and as base for X remove button styling.</reason>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>src/lib/utils.ts</path>
        <kind>utility</kind>
        <symbol>cn</symbol>
        <lines>all</lines>
        <reason>Class name merger utility (clsx + tailwind-merge). Use for conditional styling of edit button active state and genre chip disabled state.</reason>
      </artifact>
    </code>
    <dependencies>
      <node>
        <package>react</package>
        <version>18.2.0</version>
        <usage>useState for edit mode state, useEffect for existing logic</usage>
      </node>
      <node>
        <package>next</package>
        <version>14.2.3</version>
        <usage>Next.js 14 App Router, "use client" directive for interactive component</usage>
      </node>
      <node>
        <package>lucide-react</package>
        <version>0.554.0</version>
        <usage>X icon for remove button (import { X } from 'lucide-react')</usage>
      </node>
      <node>
        <package>@radix-ui/react-*</package>
        <version>1.x</version>
        <usage>Existing Radix UI components for buttons, dialogs (not needed for this story)</usage>
      </node>
      <node>
        <package>@supabase/supabase-js</package>
        <version>2.84.0</version>
        <usage>Database client for genre CRUD (existing usage, may need update for archive logic)</usage>
      </node>
      <node>
        <package>tailwindcss</package>
        <version>3.4.1</version>
        <usage>Utility classes for styling edit button, X button, disabled states</usage>
      </node>
      <node>
        <package>class-variance-authority</package>
        <version>0.7.1</version>
        <usage>CVA for button variants (existing pattern)</usage>
      </node>
      <node>
        <package>clsx + tailwind-merge</package>
        <version>latest</version>
        <usage>cn() utility for conditional class merging</usage>
      </node>
    </dependencies>
  </artifacts>

  <constraints>
    <constraint>Use existing genre-selection.tsx component structure - functional component with TypeScript</constraint>
    <constraint>Follow established patterns: "use client" directive, useState hooks, cn() for class merging</constraint>
    <constraint>Use orange color scheme from globals.css: --primary (15 100% 61%) for edit button active state</constraint>
    <constraint>Use red for X button: rgba(239, 71, 111, 0.9) or hsl(var(--destructive))</constraint>
    <constraint>Maintain 2x2 grid layout (do not change grid structure)</constraint>
    <constraint>Archive genres (soft delete) - do NOT permanently delete from database</constraint>
    <constraint>No database schema changes required (genre table already has is_active field for archiving)</constraint>
    <constraint>Keep all existing functionality intact (genre selection, showAllGenres, gradients)</constraint>
    <constraint>No new dependencies needed - use existing lucide-react X icon</constraint>
    <constraint>Story 2 (Undo Snackbar) and Story 4 (Genre Library) will enhance this feature - leave hooks for future integration</constraint>
    <constraint>No feature flag needed for this story (implement directly, unlike phonetic optimization)</constraint>
  </constraints>

  <interfaces>
    <interface>
      <name>GenreSelection Component Props</name>
      <kind>React Component Interface</kind>
      <signature>
        interface GenreSelectionProps {
          onGenreSelect?: (genreId: string, genreName: string) => void
          defaultSelectedId?: string
          selectedGenreId?: string | null
          className?: string
        }
      </signature>
      <path>src/components/genre-selection.tsx</path>
      <notes>Do not modify props interface. All edit mode logic is internal state.</notes>
    </interface>
    <interface>
      <name>Genre Type</name>
      <kind>TypeScript Interface</kind>
      <signature>
        interface Genre {
          id: string
          name: string
          display_name: string
          emoji: string | null
          sort_order: number
          gradient_colors: GradientColors | null
        }
      </signature>
      <path>src/components/genre-selection.tsx</path>
      <notes>Existing interface. Do not modify. Use id field for identifying genres to remove.</notes>
    </interface>
    <interface>
      <name>Supabase Genre Table Query</name>
      <kind>Database Query</kind>
      <signature>
        supabase
          .from('genre')
          .select('id, name, display_name, emoji, sort_order, gradient_colors')
          .eq('is_active', true)
          .order('sort_order', { ascending: true })
      </signature>
      <path>src/components/genre-selection.tsx:69-74</path>
      <notes>Existing query. For archive logic, consider updating is_active to false instead of deleting row.</notes>
    </interface>
  </interfaces>

  <tests>
    <standards>
      No test framework currently exists in codebase (confirmed via glob search). Manual testing required. Tech-spec notes: "⚠️ No test framework detected (no Jest, Vitest, etc. in package.json)" and "📝 Note: Tests should be added as part of best practices". For now, use manual testing checklist provided in story document.
    </standards>
    <locations>
      No test directories exist. If tests are added in future: src/components/__tests__/ would be recommended location for component tests.
    </locations>
    <ideas>
      <test id="AC-1" desc="Test that 'Rediger' button appears in header">Verify button renders in genre section header, positioned top-right, with pill shape and proper styling</test>
      <test id="AC-2" desc="Test clicking 'Rediger' toggles edit mode">Click button, verify state changes, text updates to 'Ferdig', background becomes orange</test>
      <test id="AC-3" desc="Test edit mode active state">Verify all AC-3 conditions: button text/color change, X buttons visible, selection disabled, cursor not-allowed</test>
      <test id="AC-4" desc="Test X button removes genre">Click X, verify genre disappears from displayGenres array, grid updates</test>
      <test id="AC-5" desc="Test soft delete/archive">Verify removed genre is archived (filter logic) not deleted from database, can be restored later (Story 4)</test>
      <test id="AC-6" desc="Test exiting edit mode">Click 'Ferdig', verify X buttons disappear, selection re-enabled, button reverts</test>
      <test id="AC-7" desc="Test edit mode persistence">Toggle on, navigate away (if applicable), verify state persists during session (until manually toggled off)</test>
      <test id="AC-8" desc="Test X button hover states">Hover over X, verify scale-up animation and darker red color transition</test>
      <test id="AC-9" desc="Test no console errors">Open DevTools, perform all actions, verify no errors or warnings logged</test>
      <test id="AC-10" desc="Test responsive design">Test on 375px mobile, 768px tablet, 1440px desktop widths, verify layout and buttons work</test>
    </ideas>
  </tests>
</story-context>
